Erwin Panofsky
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Erwin Panofsky papers
1904-1990 (bulk dates 1920-1968)
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Erwin Panofsky
19.3 cubic feet
The papers of Erwin Panofsky measure 19.3 linear feet and are dated 1904-1990 (bulk dates 1920-1968). They consist of correspondence, writings, biographical material, and printed material documenting Panofsky???s career as an art historian, teacher, and writer. The Panofsky papers are comprised mainly of correspondence with colleagues, scholars, students, art dealers, galleries and museums, libraries, colleges and universities, organizations, and periodicals.
Biographical Note
Erwin Panofsky (1892-1968), a native of Hannover, Germany, grew up in Berlin where he received a classical education at the Joachimsthalsches Gymnasium. He then studied at the universities of Berlin, Munich and Freiburg/Breslau. After earning a Ph. D. in 1914 from the University of Freiburg, Panofsky spent three years on post-doctoral study in Berlin, and during this period, married fellow student and art historian Dorothea (Dora) Mosse.
Although primarily a scholar of Gothic and Renaissance art, Panofsky had wide interests. Erwin Panofsky was a highly respected and influential scholar who was a much loved, generous, and encouraging teacher of several generations of productive scholars. Many students became his life long friends, and quite a few of them considered Panofsky the greatest teacher they had ever encountered.
He taught at the University of Hamburg from 1920 to1933, and during this period began to develop iconographic approaches to interpreting art through analysis of its subject matter's symbols, themes, and history. His work in this area eventually had international influence in the development of art history as a discipline.
Beginning in 1931, Panofsky taught at New York University, spending alternate semesters at the University of Hamburg until the Nazis dismissed all Jewish officials. He and his family fled Germany and came to the United States in 1933. During the academic year 1934/35, Panofsky held concurrent appointments at both New York University and Princeton University. He joined the faculty of the newly formed Institute for Advanced Study, Princeton, New Jersey, in 1935, where he remained until his retirement in 1962. In addition, he continued to teach graduate seminars at New York University and Princeton Universtiy.
He was a prolific writer, and his many books and articles represent some of the 20th century's most important writings in the field of art history, particularly in the realm of iconography. Among his books are: "Idea": Ein Beitrag zur Begriffsgeschichte der älteren Kunstheorie (1924) [translated later as Idea, The History of a Concept], Studies in Iconology (1939), Codex Huygens and Leonardo da Vinci's Art Theory (1940), The Life and Art of Albrecht Dürer (1943), Abbot Suger on the Abbey Church of St. Denis and Its Art Treasures (1946), Gothic Architecture and Scholasticism (1951), Early Netherlandish Painting: Its Origins and Character (1953), Meaning and the Visual Arts (1950), Renaissance and Renascences in Western Art (1960), The Iconography of Correggio's Camera di San Paolo (1961), and Problems in Titian, Mostly Iconographic (1964).
Panofsky wrote on subjects other than art history. He was an authority on Mozart, and also wrote about the history of cinema. His 1934 article "On Movies" (originally published in Princeton University's Bulletin of the Department of Art and Archaeology), remains a highly regarded work on the subject.
The recipient of numerous honorary degrees, Panofsky most prized the first from the University of Utrecht, 1936, as it brought great satisfaction at a time when he was still coping with the trauma of expatriation. He was a member of the American Philosophical Society, the American Academy of Arts and Sciences, the British Academy, and several other foreign academies. In 1962, Panofsky received the Haskins Medal awarded by The Medieval Academy of America for a distinguished book in medieval history.
His wife Dora Mosse Panofsky died in 1965; in 1966, he married Gerda Soergel, also an art historian. Erwin Panofsky died in Princeton, New Jersey, March 14, 1968.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Erwin Panofsky measure 19.3 linear feet and are dated 1904-1990 (bulk dates 1920-1968). They consist of correspondence, writings, biographical material, and printed material documenting Panofsky's career as an art historian, teacher, and writer.
The Panofsky papers are comprised mainly of correspondence with colleagues, scholars, students, art dealers, galleries and museums, libraries, colleges and universities, organizations, and periodicals. Among the correspondents are colleagues, scholars, students, art dealers, galleries and museums, libraries, colleges and universities, organizations, and periodicals. Correspondents include: Udo von Alvensleben, Walter William Spencer Cook, Paul Coremans, Walter Friedländer, William S. Heckscher, Ludwig H. Heydenreich, Horst Janson, Adolf Katzenellenbogen, Richard Krauatheimer, Edward E. Lowinsky, Millard Meiss, Gert van Osten, Richard Salomon, Craig Smyth, Wolfgang Stechow, Booth and Betty Tarkington, Egon Verheyen, and Wilhelm Vöge.
Writings by Panofsky include drafts, notes, and manuscripts of articles, book reviews, books, and lectures. Biographical material consists of awards and certificates, diplomas (including many honorary degrees), and membership certificates. Among the printed material are articles and clippings about or mentioning Panofsky, programs for graduation ceremonies at which Panofsky was awarded honorary degrees, reviews of Panofsky's books, obituaries, and memorial programs and tributes.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 4 series:
Series 1: Correspondence, 1921-1978, undated (Boxes 1-16; 16 linear ft.; Reels 2108- 2128)
Series 2: Writings, 1915-1968, undated (Boxes 17-19; 2.3 linear ft.)
Series 3: Biographical Information, 1905-1967 (Boxes 19-21; 0.5 linear ft.)
Series 4: Printed Material, 1904-1990, undated (Box 19; 0.5 linear ft.)
Related Material
Among the Archives' holdings is a collection of letters from Erwin Panofsky to art historians Wolfgang Stechow (1930-1931) and Lili Fröhlich-Bum (1931), and to Brooklyn Museum art librarian William B. Walker (1960) which is available on 35-mm microfilm reel 5136, frames 812-824. The letters to Stechow were written as he was preparing a review of Panofsky's book, Hercules am Scheidewege und andere antike Bildstoffe inder neueren Kunst, and provide additional information not found in the book itself. The letter to Mr. Walke is in Englishe, and the remainder are in German. The originals are still in the possession of Irving Lavin, who found them in Stechow's copy of Hercules am Scsheidewege given him by Mrs. Stechow.
Index Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following terms:
Subjects-Topical:
Art -- Study and teaching; Art historians -- New Jersey -- Princeton
Provenance
The Erwin Panofsky papers were donated by his widow, Dr. Gerda Soergel Panofsky, in 1979 and 1990.
Restrictions on Access
The collection is open for research. Patrons must use microfilm copy. Use of the unmicrofilmed portion requires an appointment and is limited to the Washington, D.C. research facility.
Alternative Forms Available
Series 1: Correspondence, is available on 35-mm microfilm reels 2108-2128 at Archives of American Art and through interlibrary loan.
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Correspondence, 1921-1978, undated, Series 1:; (Boxes 1-16; 16 linear ft. Reels 2108-2128)
  Erwin Panofsky's correspondence documents his research, writing, teaching, lecturing, and participation in professional organizations. It reflects his own academic interests and expertise ??? Medieval, Gothic, and Renaissance art, history, and iconography, and those of his many correspondents.
  His most prolific correspondents include: Udo von Alvensleben, Walter William Spencer Cook, Paul Coremans, Walter Friedländer, William S. Heckscher, Ludwig H. Heydenreich, Horst Janson, Adolf Katzenellenbogen, Richard Krauatheimer, Edward E. Lowinsky, Millard Meiss, Gert von der Osten, Richard Salomon, Craig Smyth, Wolfgang Stechow, Booth and Betty Tarkington, Egon Verheyen, and Wilhelm Vöge.
  1.8: Miscellaneous, arranged by subject, includes: requests for reviews, contributions to encyclopedias and dictionaries, and requests to write books; acknowledgements and thank you letters, 70th birthday congratulations; U.S. government, embassies and consulates. 1.9: Unfilmed Correspondence, received many years after microfilming was completed, is arranged chronologically and overlaps the dates and categories of correspondents represented in the preceeding subseries.
  This series is arranged into 9 subseries. Subseries 1.2, 1.3 and 1.4 are arranged alphabetically by geographical location. Subseries 1.9 is in chronological order. All remaining subseries are arranged alphabetically.
  1.1: Colleagues, Scholars, Students and Other Individuals, 1921-1978, undated (Reels 2108-2124)
  1.2: Art Dealers, 1932-1967 (Reels 2124-2125)
  1.3: Galleries and Museums, 1925-1968 (Reel 2125)
  1.4: Libraries, 1941-1967 (Reels 2125-2126)
  1.5: Colleges, Universities, and Institutes, 1936-1968, undated (Reels 2126-2127)
  1.6: Organizations, Societies, and Congresses, 1937-1967 (Reel 2127)
  1.7: Periodicals, 1937-1967 (Reel 2127)
  1.8: Miscellaneous, 1940-1969 (Reels 2127-2128)
  1.9: Unfilmed Correspondence, 1925-1967, undated (unfilmed)
  - Colleagues, Scholars, Students and Other Individuals, 1921-1978, undated, 1.1:
    - A, General (single letters, Aaron - Axinn), 1936-1966 (Box 1, Reel 2108)
      Aaron, Maxine G.
      Abbott, John E.
      Harry N. Abrams, Inc.
      Adams, Gillian
      Adler, Alfred
      Ahlborn, Richard E.
      Albers, Josef
      Albers-Schoenberg, E.
      Alef, Gustave
      Alexandr, Robert C.
      Allan, Donald J.
      Allen, D. C.
      Allen, David,
      Allenby, Amy Ingeborg
      Allers, Rudolf
      Alley, Elizabeth D.
      Altman, Julius
      Amberg, George
      Ames, Winslow
      D'Ancora
      Anderson, Edgar
      Anderson, Lawrence B.
      Anderson, Martha
      Anderson, Robert R.
      Anderson, Zane
      Andrade, D. José Pita
      Andreisse, A.
      Antal, Friedrich
      Anthony, Robert W.
      Anzelewski, Fedja
      Apel, Willi
      Aprá, Adriano
      Armstrong, Amy
      Arnold, Frederick L.
      Aronsohn, Harold N.
      Ash, Graham Baron
      Ashron, Dore
      Askew, Kirk, Jr.
      Atwood, Earle R.
      Auzas, P. M.
      Axinn, Sidney
    - Ackerman, 1947-1963 (Box 1, Reel 2108)
      Ackerman, Gerald
      Ackerman, James
    - Adams, Frederick B., Jr., 1951-1965 (Box 1, Reel 2108)
    - Adhémar, 1946-1966 (Box 1, Reel 2108)
      Adhémar, Hélène
      Adhémar, Jean
    - Alexander - Alpatov (Box 1, Reel 2108)
      Alexander, Paul J.
      Alföldi, Andrew
      Alker, Hermann
      Alpatov, Michael
    - Alvensleben, Udo von, 1928-1969, (2 folders) (Box 1, Reel 2108)
    - d'Alverny - Ameisenowa (Box 1, Reel 2108)
      d'Alverny, Marie-Thérèse
      Alyea, Herbert N.
      Ameisenowa, Zofia
    - Argan, Giulio Carlo, 1956-1968 (Box 1, Reel 2108)
    - Aries - Arnolds, 1940-1968, undated (Box 1, Reel 2108)
      Aries, Robert S.
      Arnheim, Rudolf
      Arnason, H. Harvard
      Arnolds, Günter
    - Askew - Aubert, 1952-1965 (Box 1, Reel 2108)
      Askew, Pamela
      Aubert, Marcel
    - Auerbach, Erich, 1949-1965 (Box 1, Reel 2108)
    - Aurenhammer, Hans, 1956-1967 (Box 1, Reel 2108)
    - Aydelotte, 1944-1965 (Box 1, Reel 2108)
      Aydelotte, Frank
      Aydelotte, William O.
    - B, General (single letters, Bailey - Blair), 1937-1967 (Box 1, Reel 2108)
      Bailey, Stephen K.
      Bainton, Roland H.
      Baker, Carlos
      Bannister, Turpin
      Barbour, J. Murray
      Barker, John W.
      Barnhart, Clarence L.
      Barnouw, A. J.
      Baron, H.
      Barton, Jess
      Bassi, Stelio
      Bates, Donald G.
      Baudry, J.
      Bayón, Damián Carlos
      Beaujouan, Guy
      Becker, Marion R.
      Beckley, Quitman
      Behling, Lottlisa
      Belangie, W. M.
      Belen, Van der, Jack and Herman Liebaers
      Beller, Elmer
      Bellinger, Alfred R.
      Belluschi, Pietro
      Belt, Elmer
      Berenson, Bernard [copy from S. J. Camp]
      Berg, Gösta
      Van der Berg-Noë
      Berger, Pamela
      Bergamnn, Rosemarie
      Berry, Francis
      Bertelli, Dr. and Mrs. Carlo
      Biberman, Herbert
      Bielefeld, Erwin
      Bishop, Katherine
      Blair, David
      Blair, Madeline S.
    - B, General (single letters, de Blanc - Brown), 1946-1966 (Box 1, Reel 2108)
      de Blanc, George G.
      Blanco-Gguinaga, Carlos
      Bloch, Robert
      Blom, Frans
      Blue Card, Inc.
      Bock von Wülfingen, Ordenberg
      Boehringer, Erioco
      Boggs, Jean S.
      Bonow, Eunice R.
      Bony, Mary
      Borgerhoff, E.
      Borromeo d'Adda, Contessa Orietta
      Bosi, Maria
      Böttcher, Otto
      Botte, Paul
      Bouscaren, Louis H. G.
      Bowie, Theodore
      Boyle, Kay
      Brandt, Joseph A.
      Breasted, James H., Jr.
      Breithaumpt, Erwin W.
      Brody, Jules
      Brommer, Frank
      Brooks, H. Allen, Jr.
      Brosemann, Marianne
      Brossman, Martin
      Brown, Estelle
      Brown, Harcourt
      Brown, J. Douglas
      Brown, Louise Fargo
    - B, General (single letters, Brubaker - Buxbaum), 1948-1968 (Box 1, Reel 2108)
      Brubaker, Elisabeth Ann
      Bruckmann, Verlag F.
      Bruner, Louise
      Brusselle, M. A. Fr.
      Buchholz, Sister Regina
      Buchoff, Barry
      Buchdruck, Buehler
      Buerger, Janet
      Bukofzer, Manfred F.
      Bulatkin, Eleanor W.
      Bundy, McGeorge
      Burkhardt, Frederick
      Burman, Shibdlas
      Burroughs, Alan
      Buuren, D. M. van
      Buxbaum, Rhoda
    - Bacgihofer - Badt, 1938-1967 (Box 1, Reel 2108)
      Bacgihofer, Ludwig
      Badt, Kurt
    - Baer, Kathi Meyer-Baer, 1954-1970 (Box 1, Reel 2108)
    - Baets - Bailly, 1952-1964 (Box 1, Reel 2108)
      Baets, Rev. P.M.J. de
      Baeyns, Herman
      Bailly, Ellen H.
    - Bak, Robert C., 1963-1965 (Box 1, Reel 2108)
    - Baldass - Baránszy-Jób (Box 1, Reel 2108)
      Baldass, Ludwig
      Bandmann, Günter
      Baránszy-Jób, László
    - Barasch, Moses, 1957-1969 (Box 1, Reel 2108)
    - Bardon - Barton, 1945-1964 (Box 1, Reel 2108)
      Bardon, Françoiose
      Bargebuhr, Frederick P.
      Baron, Hans
      Barton, Samuel G.
    - Barr, Alfred H., Jr. and Margaret ("Daisy"), 1945-1965, undated (Box 1, Reel 2108)
    - Barzun - Battisti, 1955-1965 (Box 1, Reel 2108)
      Barzun, Jacques
      Baticle, Jeannine
      Battisti, Eugenio
    - Bauch, Kurt, 1956-1967 (Box 1, Reel 2108-2109)
    - Bauer - Bergemann, 1951-1968 (Box 1, Reel 2108-2109)
      Bauer, Lucie
      Beck, James N
      Beckley, Rev. Quitman F.
      Begemann, Egbert Heverkamp
    - Benesch, Otto, 1945-1946 (Box 1, Reel 2108-2109)
    - Berger, Klaus, 1952-1953 (Box 1, Reel 2108-2109)
    - Bergerhoff, Renate, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Reel 2108-2109)
    - Bergström - Berliner, 1936-1964 (Box 1, Reel 2108-2109)
      Bergström, Ingvar
      Berliner, R. R.
    - Bernheimer, Richard, 1944-1957 (Box 1, Reel 2108-2109)
    - Bertin-Mourot, Thérèse, 1946-1963 (Box 1, Reel 2108-2109)
    - Bettagno - Beutler, 1961-1965 (Box 1, Reel 2108-2109)
      Bettagno, Alessandro
      Beutler, Christian
    - Bialostocki, Jan, 1953-1971 (Box 1, Reel 2108-2109)
    - Bieber, Margarete, 1941-1968 (Box 1, Reel 2108-2109)
    - Bier, Justus, 1949-1967 (Box 1, Reel 2108-2109)
    - Billikopf, Jacob, 1948 (Box 1, Reel 2108-2109)
    - Bing, Gertrude, 1925-1970 (Box 1, Reel 2108-2109)
    - Bischoff, Bernhard, 1956-1962 (Box 2, Reel 2109)
    - Birkmeyer, Karl M., 1958-1961 (Box 2, Reel 2109)
    - Björck, Gudmund, 1953 (Box 2, Reel 2109)
    - von Blanckenhagen, P. H., 1933-1967 (Box 2, Reel 2109)
    - Bloch, Peter, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Reel 2109)
    - Bloch, Vitale, 1937-1957, undated (Box 2, Reel 2109)
    - Blunt, Anthony, 1957-1967 (Box 2, Reel 2109)
    - Boas, George, 1936-1965 (Box 2, Reel 2109)
    - Bober, Harry, 1941-1965 (Box 2, Reel 2109)
    - Bober, Phyllis Pray (Mrs. Harry Bober), 1955-1959 (Box 2, Reel 2109)
    - Bodnar, Rev. Edward, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Reel 2109)
    - Bonicatti, Maurizio, 1964-1967 (Box 2, Reel 2109)
    - Bony, Jean, 1954-1964 (Box 2, Reel 2109)
    - Borsook, Eve, 1962-1966 (Box 2, Reel 2109)
    - Boskovits, Miklós, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Reel 2109)
    - Boström, Kjell, 1946-1959 (Box 2, Reel 2109)
    - Bowles, Edmund A., 1951-1963 (Box 2, Reel 2109)
    - Boyd, Juilian P., 1945-1965 (Box 2, Reel 2109)
    - Branca, Vittore, 1960-1964 (Box 2, Reel 2109)
    - Brand-Philip, Lotte (Foerster), 1949-1969 (Box 2, Reel 2109)
    - Branner, Robert, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Reel 2109)
    - Brauen, Fred, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Reel 2109)
    - Braunfels, Wolfgang, 1954-1967 (Box 2, Reel 2109)
    - Breckenridge, James, 1949-1967 (Box 2, Reel 2109)
    - Breitenbach, Edgar, 1927-1965 (Box 2, Reel 2109)
    - Brendel, Otto, 1958-1965 (Box 2, Reel 2109)
    - Briegler, Peter H., 1949-1966 (Box 2, Reel 2109)
    - Brincard, Louis, 1949-1952 (Box 2, Reel 2109)
    - Brinkerhoff, Dericksen M., 1948-1965 (Box 2, Reel 2109-2110)
    - Brion-Guérry, Liliane, 1951-1967, undated (Box 2, Reel 2109-2110)
    - Brizio, Anna Maria, circa 1950-1959 (Box 2, Reel 2109-2110)
    - Broadly, Hugh, 1950-1954 (Box 2, Reel 2109-2110)
    - Brown, Milton, 1937-1959 (Box 2, Reel 2109-2110)
    - Brummer, H. H., 1964-1965 (Box 2, Reel 2109-2110)
    - Bruyn, Josua, 1957 (Box 2, Reel 2109-2110)
    - Bucher, François, 1961-1965 (Box 2, Reel 2109-2110)
    - Buchthal, Hugo H., 1933-1966 (Box 2, Reel 2109-2110)
    - Buddensieg, Tilmann, 1958-1966 (Box 2, Reel 2109-2110)
    - Bueckenhoudt, M. Walter, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Reel 2109-2110)
    - Burden-Moller, Roland, 1953-1966 (Box 2, Reel 2109-2110)
    - Burke, William L., 1950-1959 (Box 2, Reel 2109-2110)
    - Burkhard, Arthur, 1953-1967 (Box 2, Reel 2109-2110)
    - Burrage, Bob and Mildred G., 1943-1971, undated (Box 2, Reel 2109-2110)
    - Buschbeck, Ernest, 1950-1955 (Box 2, Reel 2109-2110)
    - Bush-Brown, Albert, 1949-1958 (Box 2, Reel 2109-2110)
    - Byvanck, A. W., 1952-1956 (Box 2, Reel 2109-2110)
    - C, General (single leltters, Cabaniss - Cutler), 1937-1968 (Box 2, Reel 2109-2110)
      Cabaniss, Allen
      Calhoun, Robert L.
      Calvesi, Maurizio
      Cambrari, Archeveche de
      Caplan, Judith
      Caponigri, A. Robert
      Carey, Graham
      Carmichael, Peter A.
      Carrière, R.
      Carrith, David
      Carroll, Eugene A.
      Cassirer, Kurt
      Cassirer, Tom
      Caterini, Styde
      Cederlöf, Olle
      Cervene, Richard
      Chadraba, Rudolf
      Chadwick-Collins, Mrs. James
      Chaikin, Nathan
      Chakravarty, Amiya
      Chambers, F. P.
      Chartier, chanoine Maurice
      Cheadle, Helen
      Cirker, Hayward
      Claflin, Agnes
      Clark, John S.
      Claybrook, Priscilla Leigh
      Clements, Robert J.
      Cliver, E. Blaine
      Clogan, Paul M.
      Cloulas-Brousseau, Annie
      Coburn, Kathleen
      Coe, William J.
      Cohn, Alfred E.
      Cohn, Werner [from Millard Meiss]
      Coles, Margot J.
      Colie, Rosalie L.
      Commanger, Henry Steele
      Comstock, Francis A.
      Conan, A.
      Cooke, H. Lester
      Corbett, Dorothy
      Cornelius, Du Pont
      Cornell, Henrik
      Couprie, L. D.
      Courant, R.
      Cox, Trenchard
      Coyle, Dan
      Craig, Gordon
      Crane, Mrs. W. Murray
      Crocker, Lester G.
      Crowlie, A. C.
      Curl, Huldah
      Curran, Thomas
      Cutler, Anthony
    - Callisen - Campbell, 1951-1967 (Box 2, Reel 2109-2110)
      Callisen, Sterling A.
      Campbell, Malcolm
    - Canaday, John, 1943-1964 (Box 2, Reel 2109-2110)
    - Carandente - Cartier, 1950-1966 (Box 2, Reel 2109-2110)
      Carandente, Giobanni
      Carey, Peter, 1954-1965
      Cartier, David Giles, 1950-1962
    - Castelli - Cetto, 1951-1966 (Box 2, Reel 2109-2110)
      Castelli, Enrico
      Catlin, Stanton L.
      Cetto, Anna Maria
    - Chastel, André, 1949-1968 (Box 2, Reel 2109-2110)
    - Châtelet, Albert, 1954-1967 (Box 2, Reel 2109-2110)
    - Cherniss, Harold F., 1946-1967 (Box 2, Reel 2109-2110)
    - Chew, Samuel C. and Lucy E., 1944-1965 (Box 2, Reel 2109-2110)
    - Christie, Ives, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Reel 2109-2110)
    - Citroen - Clemens, 1951-1968 (Box 2, Reel 2109-2110)
      Citroen, K. A.
      Clagett, Marshall
      Clemens, Walter
    - Clement - Clowes, 1942-1966 (Box 2, Reel 2109-2110)
      Clement, Paul A.
      Clowes, Edith W. and Clowes, G.H.A. (The Clowes Fund)
    - Coffin, David Robbins, 1950-1967 (Box 3, Reel 2110)
    - Cohen - Cohn, 1962-1968 (Box 3, Reel 2110)
      Cohen, Bernard I.
      Cohn, Marjorie
    - Conant, Judith W., 1964-1967 (Box 3, Reel 2110)
    - Conant - Conkwright, 1951-1956 (Box 3, Reel 2110)
      Conant, Kenneth John
      Conkwright, P. J.
    - Cook, Walter William Spencer, 1937-1961, undated, (3 folders) (Box 3, Reel 2110)
    - Cooledge, Harold N., 1955 (Box 3, Reel 2110)
    - Coolidge, John, 1948-1966 (Box 3, Reel 2111)
    - Constable - Corbett, 1954-1961 (Box 3, Reel 2111)
      Constable, Giles
      Coor, Gertrude
      Corbett, James
    - Coremans, Paul, 1948-1967, (4 folders) (Box 3, Reel 2111)
    - Costello, Jane, 1946-1953 (Box 3, Reel 2111)
    - Covi, Dario Alessandro, 1953-1967 (Box 3, Reel 2111)
    - Craven - Creese, 1952-1962 (Box 3, Reel 2111)
      Craven, Wayne
      Creese, Walter L.
    - Crosby, Sumner, McK., 1941-1956 (Box 3, Reel 2111)
    - Curtis, 1959-1967, undated (Box 3, Reel 2111)
      Curtis, Ernest Robert
      Curtis, Klaus
    - Cuttler, Charles D., 1948-1957 (Box 3, Reel 2111)
    - D, General (single letters, Dacos??? Dyson), 1937-1967, (2 folders) (Box 3, Reel 2111)
      Dacos, Nichole
      Dallam, John M.
      Daly, L. J.
      David, Alfred
      Davis, Catherine
      Davis, Mrs. H. Chandler
      Davis, Howard
      Davis, Saville R.
      Dazzi, Manlio
      Dean, G. K.
      Dean, R. J.
      De Blanc, George
      De Boer, P.
      De Christoforo
      Dehn, Georg
      Delatour, G. S.
      De Laurier, Nancy Gibbon
      Delius, F.
      Della Vida, G. Levi
      Delman, Emil
      Dencher, Eva
      De Roover, Florence E.
      Dettweiler, Frieda
      Deuchlerl, Florens
      Devisse, J.
      Dickson, T. Elder
      Dieckmann, Liselotte
      Diehl, George K.
      Dihle, A.
      Diller, Hans
      Diez, Ernst
      Dingelstedt, Kurt
      Dochy, J.
      Dodwell, Reginald
      Doeblin, Alfred
      Dolan, James L.
      Donaldson, Katherine
      Donovan, James A., Jr.
      Dorner, Alexander
      Dorner, Lydia A.
      Dorsky, Morris
      Dow, Helen J.
      Downey, Glanville
      Dressler, Fridollin
      Drucker, Peter F.
      Drury, Betty
      Dubiner, Susan
      Duclos, R.
      Dufour, Alain
      Dundas, Judith
      Dyson, Freeman
    - Dahl - Dahlbäck, 1957-1966 (Box 3, Reel 2111)
      Dahl, Brother Thomas More
      Dahlbäck, Bengt
    - D'Ancona, Mirella Levi, 1947-1967, (3 folders) (Box 3, Reel 2111)
    - Davies, Martin, 1948-1968 (Box 3, Reel 2111)
    - Dean - Delanoy, 1945-1966, undated (Box 3, Reel 2111)
      Dean, Ruth J.
      Degenhart, Bernhard
      Deinzer, Willi
      Deknatel, Frederick B.
      Delanoy, Eleanor
    - Delaisé, Léon M. J., 1950-1964 (Box 3, Reel 2111)
    - Dempsey - Dewald, 1954-1967 (Box 3, Reel 2111)
      Dempsey, Charles
      Demus, Otto
      Desneux, Jules
      Dewald, Ernest T.
    - Dhanes - Dieckmann, 1952-1958 (Box 3, Reel 2111)
      Dhanes, Elisabeth
      Dibner, Bern
      Dieckmann, Herbert